Now let us understand how the mortality charges are levied on this Term Plus ULIP
type plan.
For
example, I have
taken the example of HDFC Life Insurance. The name of the plan
is Smart Protect Plan. Term Plus
ULIP also has insurance cover
like term insurance and you
also get returns like a unit linked insurance policy.
If I explain this to you through a browser,
like this is the browser of Smart Product Plan, the
mortality rules here are
called Sum at Risk (Sum at
Risk). If you want to understand that these are mortality
charges, mortality charges are
calculated at sum at risk multiplied by the
rate of mortality charges. Sum at Risk
means the risk. Sum at Risk
means the death benefit of Life Assur, which is the
insurance cover minus the
fund value. If you minus the fund value,
suppose you have taken an
insurance cover of Rs. 50 lakh, your fund value becomes Rs. 30 lakh, then the
risk is now Rs. 20 lakh, so the
mortality charges will be Rs. 20 lakh only.  Now let us
understand how this will happen, like if you see here as per the
table, if you see here that
this is a customer who is taking a policy term of 39 years, his
age is 41 years, he is paying a premium of 1 lakh for 10 years, the
basic
method is a premium of Rs. 1 lakh for him, above 50 lakh
and here
you notice that the premium is coming to Rs. 9000
along with GST, there is
also a disability cover of Rs. 50 lakh and
accidental cover of Rs. 50 lakh, if death occurs in an accident then Rs.
1 crore will be given, if disability occurs then
50 lakh will get Rs. 0000 per month for 10 years,
now here what I am
making this video for you to explain is
that you should notice that this first one is from the
table at 4, this second one is from the table at 8, as per
the IRDA norms, the
companies have to make this, the
actual returns are much higher, the returns
of the company whose product you are purchasing are from the
fund  You can see the value, for example, if
I talk about STFC, then
their average return is 14 to 15% in the last 5 to
10 years of fund performance in Yuli policies,
but on the edge numbers,
you get the tables at 4 and 8. So now
you notice, for example, here you will notice
that the mortality charges for the 10th year,
you see in the table at 4, how much is
000, but look at column number nine in the table at 8,
you will see less than here,
000. Now you notice that at 25 years the
mortality charges are 53000, but here it is
only 31000. Now you notice, if you
go a little down, that at 35th year, you see
that due to the table at 4, your
mortality charges are ₹12980, so you think
that the mortality is very high, I should not
buy the policy, whereas in the % table,
you will see that your mortality
charges are zero, because your fund value
Now it has become 55 lakhs, that is,
your fund value has become more than 50 lakhs, so
the risk is zero now, so you are
not facing any mortality charges, so
according to the table here, if you get a return of 13 14 10 12, then
very soon your mortality charges will become
zero, and whatever
mortality charges you incurred in the beginning, you get them
back double and even triple,
like for example, here
mortality charges of 9881 have been deducted,
this has been deducted here, so you will see here that it has been
written for you by addition to fund, so here
you get back all these doubled charges,
premium allocation charge, like in the
first year it is 12000, so after doubling it,
24000 is added to you, in the second year the premium
allocation charge is 6000, mortality
charge is 7000, 6 and 7 become 13 something,
so you get double of 13 something.  You got back ₹ 7000.
These charges are being refunded in this way.
So I repeat again that do
not decide not to buy your policy after looking at this table of mortality charges benefit illustration. You should understand that these
charges are being levied on sum at risk.
As your fund value increases,
mortality charges will reduce. As soon as
your point value goes up,
your insurance cover will become zero
and you will get double the motive late charges back
and after 25 to 30 years you will get
three times back. You get back the premium allocation
charges also.
You get returns as per market base. You get the
option of fund switching. You get the option of parcel withdrawal after every year. There is
no difference in your premium even in smoke rate. There are a
lot of benefits and features in this plan.
If you liked the video, then like, share,
subscribe and do
not forget to buy term insurance for your family. Thank
you so
much.